<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web3 on NTMV</title>
    <link>https://ntmv.net/tags/web3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web3 on NTMV</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ntmv.net/tags/web3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is GaGaNode And How To Run It On Mobile, Windows pc, Linux Servers (Summarized)</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/what-is-gaganode-and-how-to-run-in-on-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/what-is-gaganode-and-how-to-run-in-on-mobile/</guid>
      <description>What is gaganode? GaGaNode is a Decentralized Residential IP + Bandwidth Marketplace. With Web3.0 technology, it aims to alleviate the global shortage of IPv4 addresses. Users can participate in the Web3 network at home using Idle Electronics even if they do not have a public network IP address. Future technologies that require home bandwidth for development can obtain real home bandwidth resources via GaGa Node.
What are the advantages of running GaGaNodes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Open Service Subdaos Bring Back Helium&#39;s Glory Days?</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/can-open-service-subdaos-bring-back-heliums-glory-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/can-open-service-subdaos-bring-back-heliums-glory-days/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the decentralized web, decentralization has always been a source of contention. Some believe that the decentralized web is truly decentralized, while others believe that it is unrealistic. To be honest, I believe in second thoughts as well. One of the primary reasons for this is that decentralized web infrastructure continues to rely heavily on centralized infrastructure. Many DAPPs are still hosted on servers provided by major cloud providers such as Amazon and Google, as I mentioned in my previous article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts and Experiences On Meson - Decentralized CDN Network</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/my-thoughts-and-experiences-on-meson-decentralized-cdn-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/my-thoughts-and-experiences-on-meson-decentralized-cdn-network/</guid>
      <description>The Web is going to be decentralized. Must be. Wait, what do we need to achieve a fully decentralized future? Of course, decentralized computing and edge infrastructure. When we&amp;rsquo;re talking about Web3, there is always a silent moment for backend infrastructures. Most dapps, swaps, and even nft marketplace websites are running on big corporation-owned centralized datacenters like AWS, Google, and Azure/Microsoft. Meson is a blockchain project working to fill part of that gap.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
