<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NTMV</title>
    <link>https://ntmv.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NTMV</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ntmv.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About This Website&#39;s Content And Tech Stack</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/about-this-website-content-and-tech-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/about-this-website-content-and-tech-stack/</guid>
      <description>Posts. I usually have to do a lot of research when working on web development and cybersecurity tasks. Sometimes I find the information I&amp;rsquo;m looking for in the comments section of a website or on a personal blog, which saves me a lot of time. That&amp;rsquo;s why I just openly share my own experiences, code snippets, and some notes here. I believe that some of the information I share will benefit someone and make their job easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper Way To Install Miniflux RSS Reader on Ubuntu 22</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/proper-way-to-install-miniflux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/proper-way-to-install-miniflux/</guid>
      <description>What is Miniflux? Miniflux is my favorite RSS reader. I enjoy using it. Recently, I attempted to install the latest miniflux reader without Docker and encountered some difficulties. Installation with Docker is straightforward, but it may be necessary to install without Docker in some cases. When I looked for resources to help me solve the problems I encountered during the installation, I found no proper online installation guide. As a result, I decided to create one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is GaGaNode And How To Run It On Mobile, Windows pc, Linux Servers (Summarized)</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/what-is-gaganode-and-how-to-run-in-on-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/what-is-gaganode-and-how-to-run-in-on-mobile/</guid>
      <description>What is gaganode? GaGaNode is a Decentralized Residential IP + Bandwidth Marketplace. With Web3.0 technology, it aims to alleviate the global shortage of IPv4 addresses. Users can participate in the Web3 network at home using Idle Electronics even if they do not have a public network IP address. Future technologies that require home bandwidth for development can obtain real home bandwidth resources via GaGa Node.
What are the advantages of running GaGaNodes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress Website, But Without PHP</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/wordpress-without-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/wordpress-without-php/</guid>
      <description>What is Meson Guru? Meson.Guru is a semi-automatic news aggregator for Meson Network. You can find all the latest news, tweets, and videos about Meson Network in one place. We do not republish or store any material on our server. We simply provide a link to the relevant content.
Backed When the idea of creating such a website came to me, I decided to build my own little CMS with node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Open Service Subdaos Bring Back Helium&#39;s Glory Days?</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/can-open-service-subdaos-bring-back-heliums-glory-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/can-open-service-subdaos-bring-back-heliums-glory-days/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the decentralized web, decentralization has always been a source of contention. Some believe that the decentralized web is truly decentralized, while others believe that it is unrealistic. To be honest, I believe in second thoughts as well. One of the primary reasons for this is that decentralized web infrastructure continues to rely heavily on centralized infrastructure. Many DAPPs are still hosted on servers provided by major cloud providers such as Amazon and Google, as I mentioned in my previous article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/contact/</guid>
      <description>Fingerprint: 9893AB87CA2B7DF582D0F6B08CD527E95DF52A1E
  Download URL: ntmv.gpg
  curl -sL https://ntmv.net/keys/ntmv.gpg | gpg --import Make sure all emails from me have my digital signature on them</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/license/</guid>
      <description>I believe people should be able to find educational materials easily, share them freely with others, and reuse them as needed, without any paywalls or barriers. The content you read on this website is either my original writing or derived from my personal notes that I take while working or learning. All of my writing and posts on this blog are publicly accessible. You can freely use my articles for any good purpose under the CC BY-ND 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts and Experiences On Meson - Decentralized CDN Network</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/posts/my-thoughts-and-experiences-on-meson-decentralized-cdn-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/posts/my-thoughts-and-experiences-on-meson-decentralized-cdn-network/</guid>
      <description>The Web is going to be decentralized. Must be. Wait, what do we need to achieve a fully decentralized future? Of course, decentralized computing and edge infrastructure. When we&amp;rsquo;re talking about Web3, there is always a silent moment for backend infrastructures. Most dapps, swaps, and even nft marketplace websites are running on big corporation-owned centralized datacenters like AWS, Google, and Azure/Microsoft. Meson is a blockchain project working to fill part of that gap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://ntmv.net/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntmv.net/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
